<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Marketing on Life Beyond Rails</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/marketing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Marketing on Life Beyond Rails</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
    
    
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2013 00:00:00 UTC</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/marketing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>A Smartphone is not a Phone</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2013/02/12/a-smartphone-is-not-a-phone/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2013/02/12/a-smartphone-is-not-a-phone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve seen a number of commenters (mostly from the US) arguing that people look funny holding a 5-inch phone/tablet at the side of their heads, while being surprised at how well they&amp;rsquo;ve sold so far (especially in Asia).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it&amp;rsquo;s because those that got these &amp;ldquo;giant phones&amp;rdquo; have subconsciously realised the obvious: their smart phone isn&amp;rsquo;t a phone. It&amp;rsquo;s actually a computer that happens to have phone-like functionalities. After all, the only difference Skype has over regular cellular voice services is the medium.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m guessing all these customers have performed a cost-benefit analysis in their heads during purchase (cost of looking stupid during phone calls vs amount of time making phone calls, and the benefit of having extra screen space vs amount of time on activities that benefit from that screen space e.g. email, SMS, games, videos)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you start looking at the whole situation from this perspective, it all makes sense.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing History on Your Own Terms</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2013/02/05/writing-history-on-your-own-terms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2013/02/05/writing-history-on-your-own-terms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;HTC just posted a brilliant blog entry titled &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.htc.com/2013/02/a-brief-history-of-photography/&#34;&gt;A Brief History of Photography&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;rdquo; It&amp;rsquo;s a short infographic that details the experience of photographic technology from two centuries ago until the present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s really clever is that they&amp;rsquo;ve inserted themselves in history. The message is subtle yet clear: HTC will become part of this particular retelling of history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe your product isn&amp;rsquo;t that well known enough to be included in the &lt;strong&gt;History of Mankind&lt;/strong&gt;, or even the &lt;strong&gt;History of &lt;em&gt;insert country here&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;/strong&gt; but is there a niche or genre where you are history in the making?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The challenge then is finding out which niche or genre that is, and making sure the mark you leave behind is indelible, (enough that people will take the history you&amp;rsquo;re making as the canonical one) cementing your place in the timeline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You or your product may not be around forever, but the history you&amp;rsquo;ve contributed to is an inexpensive path to immortality.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>